hello and welcome to the 17th tutorial
on how to program a gript 2 so in this
tutorial I'm going to show you about
uploading images and using them for NPCs
and other things so for this I created a
little image called awesome
flower and it's 32x 32 pixels and it's a
PNG file it can also be a GF file if I
wanted it
to so the first thing I want to tell you
is that images and G in grow do not
allow total black and total white like
look at this this background looks black
but when you go into it it's actually
very close to Black it's slightly wider
than black like look it's not it's just
not totally black which is why it's
going to be allowed but using anything
totally white or totally black isn't
going to
work we can also use
transparents in our images that'll work
but doesn't really allow
transparencies so anyway I'm going to
close that then I'm going to go into
RC and click this little plus Square
next to the levels folder and go to
images then I'm going to upload an image
I'm going to right click anywhere I want
and upload the
image you'll see here say uploaded the
file images awesome flower.png so now
it's
there let's go into level editor and
double click on
NPC and put
set set
image awesome flower.png in
quotes if we take out these quotes it'll
think we're using a
variable we just want the name of the
image we don't want to use a variable so
we'll close that
oh I don't want to upload the level into
the images folder I want to upload into
the levels
folder so I can see here we have a
little image here and with the Collision
is automatically set to the size of the
image so a cheater or someone who wants
to cheat and go through the image can go
into the grow folder change the size of
the image to like z z and then well they
would be able to walk through it
the way to make it so that can't happen
is go into the script and put set shape
one comma 32 comma
32 this will change the size of the
image to 32 pixels by 32 pixels so X and
Y the first um number the first in the
first parameter doesn't really do
anything that I know of and you can just
set it to one which is what I always do
and this is how many pixels one tile is
16 pixels so if you do the math this
will be two tiles by two
tiles now another thing is every NPC the
0 comma 0 coordinate in them is the top
left corner so if we made it 32x 32
it'll go 32
pixels across then 32 pixels
down which is going to be like that
didn't really do anything but it wasn't
supposed to if we change to 64x
64 the image will become four tiles of
length and 30 tiles of
width as you can not
see maybe we should suppos to put it
afterwards or maybe we didn't save it
huh you how it's working now and you can
see we can't walk through
this 4x4 area we can also just make it
so it has no image and then it'll just
be an invisible wall which can which can
be good for allowing players to not
enter anything or enter past
something now let's
say well actually there's another way to
show images it's called show
image
um actually now I'm going to show you
one more thing if we put set
image it'll have a collision we can do
don't block to get rid of the Collision
so then you can walk through the
NPC or wherever the
images we can also put block again
afterwards to make it block again but by
default it's already
blocking
anyway let's put type show image 300
then awesome flower.png and quotes then
um player
x.x player
doy now this command this command can be
used in NPCs
or weapons and what it does is it
creates a image at the coordinates of
wherever you want and mine I'm going to
put it on the
player and this beginning this beginning
number is the ID of the image and I'll
show you what that does in a second
after I do this so you can see an image
appears over me but it's not going to
move anywhere when I move because it
doesn't Loop through it if we made a
loop like let's say for Loop
then it would constantly update the
position of the NPC or the image oops
the for Loop broke very quickly we want
to put
sleep one or else the for Loop is going
to break itself cuz there's a limit to
four Loops so anyway now it's following
me if you're going to be doing something
like this you usually want to use a
function
Loop like
this so we're just going to do that now
here's something else you can
do actually no I'm going to tell you
what the ID does the ID is the ID of the
image if
we waited a few
seconds then called the image Again by
the same ID number it would update the
position or the image of of whatever we
put so it's updated right there then it
waits 2 seconds and updates right there
if we change the ID to something like
301 or a number different than the
original one it's going to create a
different image so there's going to be
two flowery
images see two of
them we can also use this to delete the
image by making it the same ID then just
taking out the file and just put nothing
if we if we make the ID lower than 200
like 150 the image will be shown
throughout for everyone in the entire
level even though it's under client side
show image is just a very special
command or it can be shown server side
too so anything over 200 like
250 or 300 is going to be shown for just
the player but it's going to be a lot
smoother
looking like by smoother I mean if we
put
0.5 under under an ID of over two I mean
with an ID of over 200 it would work
here like this but with an ID of under
200 it would be rounded down to the
nearest tile and so if it was if I was
on tile um like 3 30.5 it'll get rounded
down to 30 which is why using this to
make smooth kind of images isn't a very
good idea but it still works
nevertheless and I guess that ends this
tutorial
on this ends this tutorial on how to
program gript 2 so I'll see you next
time and I think you have a better
understanding on how to call images and
use them so anyway uh bye